<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>D.I. Boomsma | Marielle Zondervan-Zwijnenburg</title>
    <link>/authors/d.i.-boomsma/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/d.i.-boomsma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>D.I. Boomsma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>D.I. Boomsma</title>
      <link>/authors/d.i.-boomsma/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian evidence synthesis in case of multi-cohort datasets: An illustration by multi-informant differences in self-control</title>
      <link>/publication/kevenaar-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/kevenaar-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing sampling bias in estimates of adolescent social competence and behavioral control</title>
      <link>/publication/fakkel-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/fakkel-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust longitudinal multi-cohort results: The development of self-control during adolescence</title>
      <link>/publication/zondervan-2020-self-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:34:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/zondervan-2020-self-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we use Bayesian evidence synthesis to evaluate how self-control develops and whether there is a gender effect on its development. We find robust support for a positive development in self-control over adolescence. Furthermore, we find mixed evidence with respect to the impact of gender. Parent-reports mainly support the hypothesis that girls have higher initial self-control than boys (but similar development). On the contrary, self-reports mostly support the hypothesis that boys have higher self-control to begin with. Are the parents stereo-typing, are the boys over-confident with respect to their own self-control, or is something else going on? Exactly because we were looking at multiple measures obtained from multiple cohorts, we were able to observe this seeming contradiction, which makes the discussion about gender in relation to self-control only more interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, all my favourite elements come together: longitudinal development, structural equation modelling, Bayesian evidence synthesis, multi-cohort data, authors with varying expertise originating from multiple research groups, and the necessary challenges with respect to missing data and differences between cohorts. I hope many projects like this will follow!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of parental age on offspring’s neurodevelopment</title>
      <link>/publication/veldkamp-zondervan-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/veldkamp-zondervan-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parental Age and Offspring Childhood Mental Health: A Multi-Cohort, Population-Based Investigation</title>
      <link>/publication/zondervan-2019-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/zondervan-2019-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article we apply Bayesian evidence synthesis to find robust evidence on the relation between parental age (both father and mother) and offspring mental health (both internalizing and externalizing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper generated world wide publicity online, in newspapers and on the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
